The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Today, we are going to do computational complexity.
教授：今天，我们要进行计算的复杂性。
This is rather different from every other thing
这与其他事物有很大的不同
we've seen in this class.
我们在这堂课上见过
This class is basically about polynomial time algorithms
此类基本上是关于多项式时间算法的
and problems where we can solve your problem
和问题，我们可以解决您的问题
in polynomial time.
在多项式时间内
And today, it's about when you can't do that.
而今天，这是您什么时候做不到的。
Sometimes, we can prove you can't do that.
有时，我们可以证明您无法做到这一点。
Sometimes, we're pretty sure you can't do that.
有时候，我们很确定您不能这样做。
But it's all about negative results
但这全都是负面的结果
when your problems are really complex.
当您的问题真的很复杂时。
And there's a lot of fun topics, here.
这里有很多有趣的话题。
This is the topic of entire classes, like 6045.
这是整个课程的主题，例如6045。
We're just going to get a 1 hour flavor of it.
我们将得到一个1小时的味道。
So think of it as a high level intro.
因此，可以将其视为高级介绍。
But we're going to prove real theorems and do real things
但是我们将证明真实定理并做真实的事情
and you'll get a sense of how all this works.
您将了解所有这些工作原理。
So I'm going to start out with three complexity classes--
所以我将从三个复杂度类开始
P, EXP, and R. How many people know what P is?
P，EXP和R。有多少人知道P是什么？
And it is?
是吗
Polynomial time.
多项式时间。
More precisely, it's the set of all problems
更确切地说，这是所有问题的集合
you can solve in polynomial time.
您可以在多项式时间内求解。
This is what the class is all about.
这就是课程的全部内容。
Almost every problem we have seen
我们几乎看到的每个问题
in this class-- there's one exception-- is
在这一堂课中-有一个例外-
in P. Does anyone know the exception?
在P中。有人知道例外吗？
It's a good puzzle for you.
这对您来说是个好难题。
Not NP.
不是NP。
What's next?
下一步是什么？
EXP.
经验值
How many people know what EXP is?
有多少人知道EXP是什么？
Or you can guess.
或者你可以猜。
Any guesses?
有什么猜想吗？
Exponential.
指数
These are all the problems you can solve in exponential time.
这些都是您可以在指数时间内解决的所有问题。
If you want to be formal about it, in this case,
如果您想对此保持正式态度，在这种情况下，
exponential means 2 to the n to some constant.
指数表示2到n的常数。
So not just 2 the n, but also 2 to the n squared, 2 to the n
因此，不仅2个n，而且2个与n平方，2个与n
cubed.
立方体。
Those are all considered-- exponential
这些都被认为-指数
and a polynomial is considered in the class EXP.
在EXP类中考虑多项式。
Now, basically, almost every problem you can dream of you
现在，基本上，您可以梦想的几乎所有问题
can solve in EXP.
可以解决EXP。
Exponential time is so much time.
指数时间是如此之多。
And this class has always been about taking things that
这堂课一直是关于
are obviously in EXP and showing that they're actually in P.
显然在EXP中，表明他们实际上在P中。
So if you want to draw a picture,
因此，如果您想画一幅画，
you could say, OK, here's all the problems
你可以说，好的，这就是所有问题
we can solve in polynomial time.
我们可以在多项式时间内求解。
Here's all the problems we can solve in exponential time.
这是我们可以在指数时间内解决的所有问题。
And there are problems out here.
这里有问题。
These are different classes.
这些是不同的类。
And we want to sort of bring things
我们想带些东西
into here as much as possible.
尽可能地进入这里。
I actually want to draw this picture
我真的想画这张画
in a different way, which is as a horizontal line.
以另一种方式，即一条水平线。
So an axis.
所以一个轴。
I'm going to call this computational difficulty.
我将这种计算难度称为“计算困难”。
You could call it computational complexity,
您可以称其为计算复杂度，
but that's a bit of a loaded term that
但这是一个负载词
actually has formal meaning.
实际上具有正式意义。
Difficulty is nice and vague.
困难是美好而模糊的。
So I can draw an abstract picture.
所以我可以画一张抽象画。
This is not a true diagram, but it's
这不是一个真正的图，但它是
a very good guideline of what's going on.
关于正在发生的事情的很好的指导方针。
So we have-- I'm going to draw-- I believe-- three notches.
因此，我们有-我要画-我相信-三个缺口。
No, eventually four, so let me give myself some room.
不，最终有四个，所以让我给自己一些空间。
We have over here, the easy problems are P. Then,
我们到了这里，简单的问题是P。然后，
we have these problems, which are EXP.
我们有这些问题，即EXP。
We're going to fill in something in the middle.
我们将在中间填充一些内容。
And then this is something called R.
然后这就是所谓的R。
So you've got P is everything, here.
因此，这里有P就是一切。
EXP is all the way out to here, in some abstract view.
从某种角度来说，EXP一直到这里。
The next thing is R. How many people know what R is?
接下来是R。有多少人知道R是什么？
This one, I had to look up.
这个，我不得不抬头。
It's not usually given a name.
通常不会给它起一个名字。
No one.
没有人。
Teaching staff?
教学人员？
You guys know it?
你们知道吗？
These are all problems solvable in finite time.
这些都是在有限时间内可以解决的问题。
R stands for finite.
R代表有限。
R stands for recursive.
R代表递归。
Recursive used to mean something completely different,
递归曾经意味着完全不同的东西，
back in the '30s, when people were thinking about what's
早在30年代，当人们在想什么
computable, what's not computable.
可计算的，不可计算的。
These are, basically, solvable problems, computable problems.
这些基本上是可解决的问题，可计算的问题。
Finite time is a reasonable requirement, I think,
我认为有限的时间是合理的要求，
for all algorithms.
适用于所有算法。
And that's R. Now, I've drawn this arrow
那是R。现在，我画了这个箭头
to keep going because there are problems out here.
继续前进，因为这里有问题。
It's kind of discouraging, but there
有点令人气,，但在那里
are problems that are unsolvable.
是无法解决的问题。
In fact, most problems are unsolvable.
实际上，大多数问题是无法解决的。
We're going to prove that.
我们将证明这一点。
It's actually really easy to prove.
实际上，这很容易证明。
Kind of depressing, but true.
有点令人沮丧，但事实如此。
Let me start with some examples before we get to that proof.
在获得证明之前，让我先举一些例子。
So I'm writing examples of some things we've seen.
所以我在写一些我们已经看到的东西的例子。
So here's an example of a problem we've seen.
因此，这是我们已经看到的一个问题的示例。
Negative-weight cycle detection.
负重循环检测。
I give you a graph-- a weighted graph.
我给你一个图-加权图。
I want to know does it have any negative-weight cycles?
我想知道它是否有负重循环？
What classes is this problem in?
这个问题在什么课上？
P. We know how to solve this in polynomial time--
P.我们知道如何在多项式时间内解决这个问题-
in VE time-- using Bellman-Ford.
VE时代-使用Bellman-Ford。
VE time-- well, that finds negative-weight cycles
VE时间-很好，找到负体重循环
reachable from s.
可从s到达。
But, I guess, if you add a source that
但是，我想，如果您添加一个源
can reach anywhere-- zero weight-- then
可以达到零重量的任何地方，然后
that'll tell you overall that it's in P.
总体上将告诉您它在P中。
It's also in EXP, of course.
当然，它也在EXP中。
Everything in P is also in EXP.
P中的所有内容也都在EXP中。
Because if you can solve it in polynomial time,
因为如果可以在多项式时间内求解，
you can solve it in exponential time.
您可以在指数时间内解决它。
This is at most exponential time.
这最多是指数时间。
At most polynomial.
最多多项式。
Here's a problem we haven't seen.
这是我们未曾见过的问题。
But it's pretty cool.
但这很酷。
N by n Chess.
国际象棋。
So this is the problem I give you.
所以这就是我给你的问题。
So we're in an by n board, and I give you
所以我们在一个n董事会中，我给你
a whole bunch of pieces on the board,
板上的一大堆碎片
and I want to know does White win from here?
我想知道怀特从这里赢了吗？
I say it's White to move or Black to move,
我说是白色移动或黑色移动，
and who's going to win form this position?
谁将从这个位置赢得胜利？
This problem, can be solved in exponential time.
这个问题，可以在指数时间内解决。
You can sort of play out all possible strategies
您可以整理出所有可能的策略
and see who wins.
看看谁赢了。
And it's not in P. There's no polynomial time algorithm
而且不在P中。没有多项式时间算法
to play generalized Chess.
玩广义象棋。
This sort of captures why Chess-- even at eight by eight
这种记录说明了为什么国际象棋-即使是八乘八
Chess-- is hard-- because there's no general way
象棋-很难-因为没有通用的方法
to do it.
去做吧。
So there's no special way to do it, probably.
因此，可能没有特殊的方法可以做到这一点。
Computational complexity is all about order of growth.
计算复杂性全与增长顺序有关。
So we can't analyze eight by eight Chess,
因此，我们无法分析八乘八的国际象棋，
but we can analyze n by n Chess.
但是我们可以用n Chess来分析n
And that gives us a flavor of why 8 by 8 is so difficult.
这使我们明白了为什么8乘8如此困难。
Go is also in EXP, but not in P-- lots of games
Go也出现在EXP中，但不在P中-很多游戏
are in this category, lot's of complicated games, let's say.
可以说，这类游戏非常复杂。
And so this is a first example of a problem that we know we
这是我们知道的第一个问题示例
cannot solve in polynomial time.
不能在多项式时间内求解。
Bad news.
坏消息。
I also talked about Tetris a little bit.
我还谈到了俄罗斯方块。
Unlike the Tetris training, which we saw,
与我们看到的俄罗斯方块训练不同，
this is sort of realistic Tetris--
这是一种现实的俄罗斯方块-
all the rules of Tetris.
俄罗斯方块的所有规则。
The only catch is that I tell you all the pieces that
唯一的收获是我告诉你所有的碎片
are going to come in advance.
将会提前。
Because, otherwise, it's some random process
因为，否则，这是一个随机过程
and it's kind of hard to think about what's the best strategy.
而且很难考虑什么是最佳策略。
But if I tell you what's going to come--
但是，如果我告诉你会发生什么……
say it's a pseudo-random generator
说这是伪随机生成器
and you know how it works.
而且您知道它是如何工作的。
You know all the pieces that will come.
您知道将要发生的所有事情。
I want to know can I survive from a given initial board mess
我想知道我能否在给定的初始董事会混乱中生存
and for a given sequence of pieces.
和给定的片段顺序。
This can also be solved in exponential time.
这也可以在指数时间内解决。
Just try all the possibilities.
只要尝试所有可能性。
We don't know whether it's in P. We're pretty sure
我们不知道它是否在P中。我们很确定
it's not in P. And by the end of today's lecture,
它不在P中。在今天的演讲结束时，
you'll understand why we think it's not in P.
您将了解为什么我们认为它不在P中。
But it's going to be somewhere in between here.
但这将介于两者之间。
Tetris is actually right here.
俄罗斯方块实际上就在这里。
But I haven't defined what right here is yet.
但是我还没有定义这里的内容。
And then the next one is halting problem.
然后下一个是停止问题。
So halting problem is particularly cool,
因此，暂停问题特别酷，
as we'll see-- or interesting.
如我们所见-或很有趣。
It's the problem of given a computer program-- Python,
这是给定计算机程序的问题-Python，
whatever, it doesn't really matter what language.
随便什么语言都没关系
They're all the same in a theoretical sense--
从理论上讲，它们都是一样的-
does it ever halt?
有没有停止过？
Does it ever stop running, return a result, whatever?
它会停止运行，返回结果吗？
This would be really handy-- you're writing some code,
这真的很方便-您正在编写一些代码，
and you've run it for 5 hours, and you
您已经运行了5个小时，而您
don't know is that because there's a bug
不知道是因为有错误
and you've got an infinite loop?
你有一个无限循环？
Or is it just because it's really slow?
还是仅仅是因为它真的很慢？
So you'd like to give it to some program-- checking
所以您想将其提供给某些程序-检查
program-- that says will this run forever
程序-这将永远运行
or will it terminate.
否则它将终止。
That's the halting problem.
那是停顿的问题。
And this problem is not in R. There
而且这个问题不在R中。
is no correct algorithm for solving this problem.
没有解决此问题的正确算法。
There's no way to tell, given an arbitrary program,
在任意程序的情况下，无法分辨
whether it will halt.
是否会停止。
Now, in some situations-- take the empty program--
现在，在某些情况下-选择空程序-
I can tell that it halts.
我可以说它停止了。
Or I take some special simple class of programs,
或者我选一些特别简单的程序
I can tell whether they halt or determine that they don't halt.
我可以告诉他们是停止还是确定他们不停止。
But there's no algorithm that solves it for all programs,
但是没有一种算法可以解决所有程序，
in finite time.
在有限的时间内。
In infinite time, I can solve it.
在无限时间内，我可以解决它。
Just run it.
只是运行它。
Run the program.
运行程序。
Given finite time, there's no way to solve this.
在有限的时间内，无法解决此问题。
And so this is a little bit beyond what we can prove today.
因此，这超出了我们今天可以证明的范围。
It's not that hard to prove, but it
证明并不难，但是
takes half an hour or something.
需要半个小时左右。
I want to get to other things.
我想了解其他事情。
But if you take 6045, they'll prove this.
但是，如果您使用6045，他们会证明这一点。
What I want to show you instead is an easier
我想告诉你的是更容易的
result-- that almost every problem is not in R.
结果-几乎每个问题都不在R中。
I need one term, though, which is decision problems.
不过，我需要一个术语，即决策问题。
All of these problems, I set it up in a way
所有这些问题，我都将其设置为
that the answer is binary-- yes or no.
答案是二进制的-是或否。
Is there a negative-weight cycle?
是否存在负体重循环？
Yes or no?
是还是不是？
Does White win from this position in Chess?
怀特会从国际象棋这个位置获胜吗？
Can you survive in Tetris?
你可以在俄罗斯方块生存吗？
And does this program halt?
并且该程序停止了吗？
For various reasons-- basically convenience--
由于各种原因-基本上是方便-
the whole field of computational complexity
计算复杂度的整个领域
focuses on decision problems.
专注于决策问题。
And, in fact-- so decision problems
而且，事实上-决策问题
are ones where the answer is yes or no.
是答案为是或否的答案。
That's all.
就这样。
Why?
为什么？
Essentially because it doesn't matter.
本质上是因为这无关紧要。
If you take a problem you care about,
如果您担心自己遇到的问题，
you can convert it into a decision problem.
您可以将其转换为决策问题。
We can see examples of that later.
我们稍后会看到示例。
Decision problems are basically as
决策问题基本上是
hard as optimization problems or whatever.
作为优化问题或其他困难。
But let's focus on decision problems.
但是，让我们关注决策问题。
The answer is yes or no.
答案是是或否。
Claim that most of them are uncomputable.
声称其中大多数没有争议。
And we can prove this pretty easily
我们可以很容易地证明这一点
if you know a bit of set theory, I guess.
如果您了解一些集合论，我想。
On the one hand, I have problems I want to solve.
一方面，我有要解决的问题。
These are decision problems.
这些是决策问题。
And on the other hand, I have algorithms,
另一方面，我有算法
or computer programs to solve them.
或计算机程序来解决它们。
I'm going to think of computer programs
我要考虑计算机程序
because more precise algorithms can
因为更精确的算法可以
be a little bit nebulous for thinking about pseudocode--
对于伪代码的思考有点模糊-
what's valid, what's invalid.
什么是有效的，什么是无效的。
But computer programs are very clear.
但是计算机程序非常清楚。
I give you some code.
我给你一些代码。
You throw it into Python.
您将其放入Python。
Either it works or it doesn't.
它要么起作用，要么不起作用。
And it does something.
而且它有作用。
Runs for a while.
运行一段时间。
How can I think about the space of all possible programs?
我如何考虑所有可能程序的空间？
Well, programs are things you type into a computer
好吧，程序就是您输入计算机的东西
in ASCII, whatever.
以ASCII格式表示。
In the end, you can think of it as just as a binary string.
最后，您可以将其视为二进制字符串。
Somehow it gets encoded in binary.
它以某种方式被编码为二进制。
Everything is reduced to binary in the end, on a computer.
最后，在计算机上所有内容都简化为二进制。
So this is a binary string.
所以这是一个二进制字符串。
Now, you can also think of a binary string
现在，您还可以想到一个二进制字符串
as representing a number, in binary.
以二进制形式表示数字。
So you can also think of a program,
所以您也可以想到一个程序
then, as a natural number-- some number between 0 and infinity.
然后，作为自然数-0到无穷大之间的某个数字。
And an integer.
和一个整数。
So usually we represent this as math bold N.
因此通常我们将其表示为数学粗体N。
That's just 0, 1, 2, 3.
就是0、1、2、3。
You can think of every program is ultimately
您可以想到每个程序最终
reducing to an integer.
减少为整数。
It's a big integer, but, hey.
这是一个大整数，但是，嘿。
It's an integer.
这是一个整数。
So that's the space of all programs.
这就是所有程序的空间。
Now, I want to think about the space of all decision problems.
现在，我想考虑所有决策问题的空间。
So how can I define a decision problem?
那么如何定义决策问题呢？
Well, the natural way to think of a decision problem
好吧，思考决策问题的自然方法
is as a function that maps inputs to yes or no.
是将输入映射为是或否的函数。
Function from inputs to yes or no.
从输入到是或否的功能。
Or you can think of that as 1 and 0.
或者，您可以将其视为1和0。
So what's an input?
那么输入是什么？
Well, an input is a binary string.
嗯，输入是一个二进制字符串。
So an input is a number-- a natural number.
因此，输入就是一个数字-一个自然数。
Input is a binary string, which we can think of as being in N.
输入是一个二进制字符串，我们可以认为它是N。
So we've got a function from N to 0,1.
因此我们有一个从N到0,1的函数。
So another way to represent one of these functions
所以代表这些功能之一的另一种方法
is as a table.
是一张桌子。
I could just write down all the answers.
我可以写下所有答案。
So I've got, well, the input could be 0-- the number 0.
所以我得到的输入可以是0-数字0。
And then, maybe it's a 0.
然后，可能是0。
Input could be could be 1 and then, maybe, output is 0.
输入可能是1，然后输出可能是0。
Then, the input could be 2, 3, 4, 5, 1, 0, 1, 1, whatever.
然后，输入可能是2、3、4、5、1、0、1、1。
So I could write the table of all answers.
所以我可以写所有答案的表。
This is another way to write down such a function.
这是写下这种功能的另一种方式。
What we have, here, is an infinite string of bits.
在这里，我们拥有的是无限的比特串。
Each of them could be 0 or 1.
它们每个可以是0或1。
It would be a different problem.
这将是一个不同的问题。
But they all exist.
但是它们都存在。
Any infinite string of bits represents a decision problem.
任何无限的比特串都代表决策问题。
They're the same thing.
他们是同一回事。
So a decision problem is an infinite string of bits.
因此，决策问题是无限的位字符串。
A program is a finite string of bits.
程序是有限的位字符串。
These are different things.
这些是不同的东西。
One way to see that they're different
看到他们与众不同的一种方式
is put a decimal point, here.
在这里放一个小数点。
Now, this infinite string of bits
现在，这无限的比特串
is a number-- a real number-- between 0 and 1.
是介于0和1之间的数字-实数。
It's written in binary.
它用二进制编写。
You may not be used to binary point.
您可能不习惯二进制点。
This dot is not a decimal point.
该点不是小数点。
It's a binary point.
这是一个二进制点。
But, hey.
但是，嘿。
Any real number can be expressed by an infinite string of bits
任何实数都可以由无限的位字符串表示
in this way-- any real number between 0 and 1.
以这种方式-0到1之间的任何实数
So a decision problem is basically
所以决策问题基本上是
something in R, the set of all real numbers,
R中的所有实数集
whereas a program is something in N, the set of all integers.
而程序是N中的所有整数。
And the thing is, the number of real numbers
问题是实数
is much, much bigger than the number of integers.
比整数的数量大得多。
In a formal sense, we call this one uncountably infinite,
从正式意义上讲，我们称其为无限，
and this one is countably infinite.
而这一点是无限的。
I'm not going to prove that here, today.
我今天不会在这里证明这一点。
You may have seen that proof.
您可能已经看到了这一证明。
It's pretty simple.
很简单
And that's bad news.
那是个坏消息。
That means that there are way more problems
这意味着还有更多问题
than there are programs to solve them.
而不是有解决方案。
So this means almost every problem that we could conceive
所以这意味着我们可以想到的几乎所有问题
of is unsolvable by every program.
每个程序都无法解决。
And this is pretty depressing the first time I saw it.
这是我第一次看到它时非常沮丧。
That's why we put it at the end of the class.
这就是为什么我们将其放在课程末尾。
I think you get all existential.
我想你们都存在。
I mean the thing is every program only
我的意思是，只有每个程序
solves one problem.
解决了一个问题。
It takes some input, and it's either
它需要一些输入，或者是
going to output yes or no.
将输出是或否。
And if it's wrong on any of the inputs, then it's wrong.
而且，如果在任何输入上都错了，那就错了。
So it's going to give an answer.
因此，它将给出一个答案。
Say it's a deterministic algorithm.
说这是确定性算法。
No random numbers or things.
没有随机数或事物。
Then, there's just not enough programs
那就是程序不够
to go around if each program only solves one problem.
如果每个程序都只能解决一个问题，那就去解决。
This is the end of the proof.
证明到此结束。
Any questions about that?
对此有任何疑问吗？
Kind of weird.
有点奇怪。
Because yet somehow, most of the problems that we think about
因为无论如何，我们考虑的大多数问题
are computable.
是可计算的。
I don't know why that is.
我不知道为什么。
But mathematically, most problems
但是从数学上讲，大多数问题
that you could think of are uncomputable.
您可能认为这是无可争议的。
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
It's something like, the way that we describe
就像我们描述的方式
problems is usually almost algorithmic, anyway.
无论如何，问题通常几乎都是算法上的。
And so, usually, most problems we think of are in EXP.
因此，通常，我们想到的大多数问题都在EXP中。
And so they're definitely computable.
因此，它们绝对是可计算的。
There's some metatheorem about how
关于如何有一些元定理
we think about problems, not just programs.
我们不仅考虑程序，还考虑问题。
So that's all I'm going to say about R. So out here,
这就是我要说的R。所以在这里，
we have halting problem and, actually, most problems.
我们有停顿的问题，实际上是大多数问题。
You can think of this as an infinite line
您可以将其视为一条无限线
and then there's just this small portion
然后只有一小部分
which are things you can solve.
您可以解决的问题。
But we care about this portion because that's
但是我们关心这部分，因为那是
the interesting stuff.
有趣的东西。
That's what algorithms are about.
这就是算法的意义所在。
Out here kind of nothing happens.
在这里什么也没发生。
So I want to talk about this notch, which is NP.
所以我想谈谈这个缺口，即NP。
I imagine you've heard about NP.
我想您已经听说过NP。
It's pretty cool, but also kind of confusing.
这很酷，但也有点令人困惑。
But it's actually very closely related to something
但这实际上与某件事密切相关
we've seen with dynamic programming, which is guessing.
我们已经看到了动态编程，这是猜测。
So I'm going to give you a couple of definitions
所以我要给你几个定义
of NP-- not formal definition, but high level definitions.
NP的定义-不是正式定义，而是高级定义。
So just like P, EXP, and R, it's a set of decision problems.
因此，就像P，EXP和R，这是一组决策问题。
And it's going to look very similar to P. NP does not
它看起来与P非常相似。NP不
stand for not a polynomial.
代表不是多项式。
It stands for nondeterministic polynomial.
它代表不确定的多项式。
We'll get to nondeterministic in a moment.
一会儿我们将变得不确定。
The first line is the same.
第一行是相同的。
It's all decision problems you can solve in polynomial time.
您可以在多项式时间内解决所有决策问题。
That sounds like P. But then, there's
听起来像P。但是然后，
this extra line, which is via a "lucky" algorithm.
这条额外的线是通过“幸运”算法完成的。
Let me tell you-- at a high level what
让我告诉您-高层次
a lucky algorithm does is it can make guesses.
幸运的算法确实可以做出猜测。
But unlike the way that we've been making guesses
但是与我们一直在猜测的方式不同
with dynamic programming-- with dynamic programming
动态编程-动态编程
we had to guess something.
我们不得不猜测一些事情。
We tried all the possibilities.
我们尝试了所有可能性。
A lucky algorithm just needs to try one possibility
幸运算法只需要尝试一种可能性
because it's really lucky.
因为真的很幸运
It always guesses the right choice.
它总是猜测正确的选择。
It's like magic.
就像魔术。
This is not a realistic model of computation,
这不是现实的计算模型，
but it is a model of computation called nondeterministic model.
但这是一种计算模型，称为非确定性模型。
And it's going to sound crazy because it is crazy,
听起来会很疯狂，因为它很疯狂，
but nonetheless it's actually really useful--
但尽管如此，它实际上确实非常有用-
even though you could never really build
即使你永远无法真正建造
this on a real computer.
在真实的计算机上。
The nondeterministic model is not
非确定性模型不是
a model of real computation.
真实计算的模型。
It is a model of theoretical hypothetical computation.
它是理论假设计算的模型。
It gets at the root-- at the core
它扎根-核心
of what is possible to solve.
有什么可能解决的。
You'll see why, in a little bit.
稍后，您会明白为什么。
So in this model, an algorithm-- it can compute stuff,
因此，在此模型中，一种算法-它可以计算东西，
but, in particular, it makes guesses.
但是，它尤其让人猜测。
So should I do this or should I do this?
那么我应该这样做还是应该这样做？
And it just says-- It doesn't flip a coin.
它只是说-它不会掷硬币。
It's not random.
这不是随机的。
It just thinks-- it just makes a guess.
它只是在想-这只是一个猜测。
Well, I don't know.
好吧，我不知道。
Let's go this way.
我们这样走吧。
And then it comes another fork in the road.
然后它又出现了。
It's like, well, I don't know.
就像，嗯，我不知道。
I'll go this way.
我走这边。
That's the guessing.
那是猜测。
You give it a list of choices and somehow a choice
您给它一个选择列表，以某种方式选择
is determined, by magic-- nondeterministic magic.
是由魔法-非确定性魔法决定的。
And then the fun part is-- I should say, at the end
最后，有趣的部分是-我应该说
the algorithm either says yes or no.
该算法说是或否。
It gives you an output.
它给您输出。
The guesses are guaranteed-- this is the magic part--
猜测得到保证-这是不可思议的部分-
to lead to a yes answer, if possible.
如果可能的话，得出肯定的答案。
So if you imagine the space of executions of this program,
因此，如果您想象该程序的执行空间，
you start here, and you make some guess and you
你从这里开始，你会猜一猜，你
don't know which way to go.
不知道走哪条路。
In dynamic programming, we try all of them.
在动态编程中，我们尝试所有这些。
But this algorithm doesn't try all of them.
但是此算法不会尝试所有方法。
It's like a branching universe model of the universe.
就像是宇宙的分支宇宙模型。
So you make some choice, and then you
所以你做出一些选择，然后你
make some other choice, and then you make some other choice.
做出其他选择，然后再做出其他选择。
All of these are guesses.
所有这些都是猜测。
And some of these things will lead to yes.
这些事情中的一些将导致是。
Some of these things will lead to no.
这些事情中的一些将导致没有。
And in this magical model, if there's any yes out there,
在这个神奇的模型中，如果有任何答案，
you will follow a path to a yes.
您将遵循“是”的道路。
If all of the answers are no, then, of course,
如果所有答案都不是，那当然
it doesn't matter what choices you make.
做出什么选择都没有关系。
You will output no.
您将输出编号。
But if there's ever a yes, magically these guesses
但是，如果有的话，神奇的是这些猜测
find it.
找到它。
This is the sense of lucky.
这是幸运的感觉。
If you're trying to find a yes-- that's your goal in life--
如果您想找到一个是您的人生目标，
then this corresponds to luck.
那么这相当于运气。
And NP is the class of all problems solvable
NP是所有可解决问题的类别
in polynomial time by a really lucky algorithm.
在多项式时间内通过一个非常幸运的算法。
Crazy.
疯。
I know.
我知道。
Let's talk about Tetris.
让我们谈谈俄罗斯方块。
Tetris, I claim, is in NP.
我声称俄罗斯方块在NP中。
And we know how to solve it in exponential time.
我们知道如何在指数时间内解决问题。
Just try all the options.
只需尝试所有选项。
But, in fact, I don't need to try all the options.
但是，实际上，我不需要尝试所有选项。
It would be enough just use this nondeterministic magic.
仅使用这种不确定的魔术就足够了。
I could say, well, should I drop the piece here, here, here,
我可以说，好吧，我应该在这里，这里，这里丢下一块吗？
here, here, or here.
这里，这里或这里。
And should it be rotated like this, or like this,
并且应该像这样旋转，
or like this, or like this?
还是喜欢这个，或者喜欢这个？
I don't know.
我不知道。
So I guess.
所以我猜。
And I just place that piece.
我只是把那一块。
I make another guess where to place the next piece.
我又猜测下一块应该放在哪里。
Then I make another guess where to place the next piece.
然后，我又猜测下一块的位置。
I implement the rules of Tetris, which
我执行俄罗斯方块的规则
is if there's a full line it clears.
如果有一个完整的行，它会清除。
I figure out where these things fall.
我弄清楚这些东西在哪里。
I can even think about, should I rotate at the last second.
我什至可以考虑，是否应该在最后一秒旋转。
If I don't know, I'll guess.
如果我不知道，我会猜测。
Any choice you have to make in playing Tetris,
在玩俄罗斯方块时，您必须做出任何选择，
you can just guess.
您可以猜测。
There's only polynomially many guesses you need to make.
您只需做出多项式的猜测。
So it's still polynomial time.
所以现在仍然是多项式时间。
That's important.
那很重要
It's not like we can do anything.
并不是说我们可以做任何事情。
But we can make a polynomial number these magic guesses.
但是我们可以用这些神奇的猜测得出一个多项式数。
And then at the end, I determine did I die--
最后，我确定我死了-
or rather, did I survive.
还是我生存了下来
It's important, actually.
实际上，这很重要。
It only works one way.
它仅以一种方式起作用。
Did I survive?
我还活着吗
Yes or no?
是还是不是？
And that's easy to compute.
这很容易计算。
I just see did I ever go above the top row.
我只是看到我曾经超过第一行。
So what this model says is if there is any way
所以这个模型说的是
to survive-- if there is any way to get a yes answer,
生存-如果有任何办法可以得到肯定的答案，
then, my guesses will find it, magically, in this model.
然后，我的猜测将在此模型中神奇地找到它。
Therefore, Tetris is in NP.
因此，俄罗斯方块在NP中。
If I had instead said, did I die, then,
如果我改为说我死了，那么，
what this algorithm would tell me is there any way
这个算法会告诉我什么
to die-- which, the answer's probably yes,
死了-答案可能是肯定的，
unless you're given a really trivial input.
除非您得到的是非常琐碎的输入。
So it's important you set up the yes versus no, correctly.
因此，正确设置是与否非常重要。
But the Tetris decision problem "can I survive," is in NP.
但是，俄罗斯方块的决策问题“我能生存吗”在NP中。
The decision problem "can I die," should not be in NP.
决策问题“我可以死”不应该存在于NP中。
But we don't know.
但是我们不知道。
Another way to think about NP.
思考NP的另一种方法。
And you might find this intuitive
而且您可能会发现这很直观
because we've been doing lots of guessing.
因为我们一直在猜测。
It's just a little crazy.
有点疯狂。
There's another way that's more intuitive to many people.
对于许多人来说，还有另一种方式更直观。
So if this doesn't make sense, don't worry, yet.
因此，如果这没有意义，请不要担心。
This is another way to phrase it.
这是另一种表达方式。
Another way to think about NP-- which turns out
思考NP的另一种方法-结果
to be equivalent-- is that don't think so much about algorithms
等价的是-对算法的考虑不多
for solving a problem, just think about algorithms
要解决问题，只需考虑算法
for checking the solution to a problem.
用于检查问题的解决方案。
It's usually a lot easier to check your work
通常检查工作要容易得多
than it is to solve a problem in the first place.
而不是首先解决问题。
And NP is all about that issue.
NP就是关于这个问题的。
So think of decision problems and think
因此，思考决策问题并思考
about if you have a solution-- so let's say in Tetris,
关于您是否有解决方案-假设在俄罗斯方块中，
the solution is yes.
解决方案是。
In fact, I need to say this, probably.
实际上，我可能需要这么说。
The more formal version is whenever
更正式的版本是
the answer is yes, you can prove it.
答案是肯定的，您可以证明这一点。
And you can check that proof in polynomial time.
您可以在多项式时间内检查该证明。
This is the more formal-- this a little bit high level.
这比较正式-有点高水平。
What does check mean?
检查是什么意思？
Here's what check means.
这就是检查的意思。
Whenever an answer is "yes," you can write down a proof
只要答案是“是”，您就可以写下证明
that the answer is yes.
答案是肯定的。
And someone can come along and check
有人可以过来检查
that proof in polynomial time and be convinced
证明多项式时间并被说服
that the answer is yes.
答案是肯定的。
What does convinced mean?
说服是什么意思？
It's not that hard.
没那么难。
Think of it is a two player game.
认为这是一个两人游戏。
There's me trying to play Tetris,
我在尝试玩俄罗斯方块，
and there's you trying to be convinced
而你试图说服
that I'm really good at Tetris.
我真的很擅长俄罗斯方块。
It seems a little one sided, but-- it's a asymmetric game.
似乎有些反面，但是-这是一个不对称的游戏。
So you want to prove Tetris is-- I want to show Tetris is in NP.
所以你想证明俄罗斯方块是-我想证明俄罗斯方块在NP中。
Imagine I'm this magical creature.
想象我是这个神奇的生物。
Actually, it's kind of funny.
实际上，这很有趣。
It reminds me of a story.
它使我想起一个故事。
On the front of my office door, you
在我办公室门的前面，你
may have seen there's an email I received,
可能看到我收到了一封电子邮件，
maybe 15 years ago-- oh no, I guess
也许15年前-哦不，我猜
it can't be that long ago.
不可能那么久。
Must've been about 7 years ago when
一定是在7年前
we proved that Tetris is NP-complete.
我们证明了俄罗斯方块是NP完全的。
And the email says, "Dear Sir,"-- or whatever--
电子邮件中说：“亲爱的先生”，或其他任何内容，
"I am NP-complete."
“我很NP。”
We don't what NP-complete means, yet,
我们不是NP-complete的意思，
but it's a meaningless statement.
但这是毫无意义的声明。
So it doesn't matter that you don't know what it means.
因此，您不知道这意味着什么都没关系。
It might get funnier throughout the lecture today.
今天的整个讲座可能会更有趣。
And he's like, I can solve Tetris.
他就像，我可以解决俄罗斯方块。
I'm really good at playing Tetris.
我真的很擅长玩俄罗斯方块。
I'm really good at playing Minesweeper--
我真的很擅长打扫雷
all these games that are thought to be intractable.
所有这些被认为是棘手的游戏。
He gave me his records and so on.
他给了我他的记录，依此类推。
It's like how can I apply my talent.
就像我该如何运用自己的才能。
So I will translate what he meant to say was, "I am lucky."
因此，我将翻译他的意思是“我很幸运”。
And this is probably not true, but he
这可能不是真的，但是他
thought that he was lucky.
以为他很幸运。
He wanted to convince me he was lucky.
他想说服我他很幸运。
So how could we do it?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
Well, I could give him a really hard Tetris problem.
好吧，我可以给他一个非常困难的俄罗斯方块问题。
And say, can you survive these pieces?
再说，你能生存下来吗？
And he says, "yes, I can survive. "
他说：“是的，我可以生存。”
And how does he prove to me that he can survive?
他如何向我证明自己可以生存？
Well, he just plays it.
好吧，他只是玩。
He shows me what to do.
他告诉我该怎么办。
So proof is sequence of moves that you make.
因此，证明就是您所做的一系列动作。
It's really easy to convince someone
说服某人真的很容易
that you can survive a given level of Tetris.
您可以在给定水平的俄罗斯方块中生存。
You just show what the sequence of moves are.
您只需要显示移动顺序即可。
And then I, as a mere mortal polynomial time algorithm
然后我，作为一个凡人多项式时间算法
can check that that sequence works.
可以检查该序列是否有效。
I just have to implement the rules of Tetris.
我只需要执行俄罗斯方块的规则。
So in Tetris, the rules are easy to implement.
因此，在俄罗斯方块中，规则很容易实现。
Its the knowing what thing to do is hard.
知道要做什么是很难的。
But in NP, knowing which way to go is easy.
但是在NP中，知道走哪条路很容易。
In this version, you don't even talk
在这个版本中，您甚至都不会说话
about how to find the solution.
关于如何找到解决方案。
It's just a matter of can you write down
你可以写下来
a solution that can be checked.
可以检查的解决方案。
Can prove it.
可以证明这一点。
This is not in polynomial time.
这不是多项式时间。
You get arbitrarily much time to prove it.
您可以任意花很多时间来证明这一点。
But then, the check has to happen in polynomial time.
但是随后，检查必须在多项式时间内进行。
Kind of clear?
有点清楚吗？
That's Tetris.
那是俄罗斯方块。
And every problem that you can solve in polynomial
以及多项式可以解决的所有问题
time you can also, of course, check it.
时间，您当然也可以进行检查。
Because if you could solve it in polynomial time,
因为如果可以在多项式时间内求解，
you could just solve it and then see
你可以解决它，然后看
did you get the same answer that I did.
你得到的答案和我一样。
So P is inside NP.
所以P在NP内部。
But the big question is does p equal NP.
但是最大的问题是p是否等于NP。
And most people think no.
大多数人认为不。
P does not equal NP-- most sane people.
P不等于NP-大多数理智的人。
So this is a big problem.
因此，这是一个大问题。
It's one of the famous Millennium Prize problems.
这是著名的千年奖问题之一。
So in particular, if you solved it, you would get $1 million,
因此，特别是，如果您解决它，您将获得100万美元，
and fame, and probably other fortune.
和名望，也许还有其他财富。
You could do TV spots.
您可以做电视节目。
I think that's how people mostly make their money.
我认为人们就是这样赚钱的。
You could do a lot.
你可以做很多事。
You would become the most famous computer scientist in the world
您将成为世界上最著名的计算机科学家
if you prove this.
如果你证明这一点。
So a lot of people have tried.
所以很多人都尝试过。
Every year, there's an attempt to prove either
每年都有尝试证明
what everyone believes or, most often,
每个人都相信或最常
people try to prove the reverse-- that they are equal.
人们试图证明相反的事实-他们是平等的。
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么
They should bet the other way.
他们应该反赌。
So what does P does not equal NP mean?
那么P不等于NP是什么意思？
It means that there are problems, here, that are in NP
这意味着这里存在NP中的问题
but not in P. Think about what this means.
但请不要在P中考虑。
This is saying P are the problems that we can actually
这就是说P是我们实际上可以解决的问题
solve on a legitimate computer.
在合法计算机上解决。
NP are problems that we can solve in this magical fairy
NP是我们在这个神奇仙女中可以解决的问题
computer where all of our dreams are granted.
实现我们所有梦想的计算机。
You say, oh, I don't know which way to go.
你说，哦，我不知道走哪条路。
It doesn't matter because the machine magically
没关系，因为机器神奇
tells you which way to go.
告诉您要走的路。
If you're goal is to get to a yes.
如果您的目标是获得肯定。
So NP is a really powerful model of computation.
因此，NP是一个非常强大的计算模型。
It's an insane model of computation.
这是一个疯狂的计算模型。
No one in their right mind would consider it legitimate.
在他们的正确思想中，没有人会认为这是合法的。
So obviously, it's more powerful than P,
所以很明显，它比P更强大，
except we don't know how to prove it.
除了我们不知道如何证明。
Very annoying.
很烦人。
Other phrasings of P does not equal
P的其他措词不等于
NP is-- these are my phrasings, I them up-- you
NP是-这些是我的措辞，我是他们-你
can't engineer luck.
不能运气。
You can believe in luck, if you want.
如果愿意，您可以相信运气。
But it's not something that we can build out
但这不是我们可以建立的东西
of a regular computer.
普通计算机。
That's the meaning of this statement.
这就是声明的意思。
And so I think most people believe that.
因此，我认为大多数人都相信这一点。
Another phrasing would be that solving problems
另一个说法是解决问题
is harder than checking solutions.
比检查解决方案难。
A more formal version is that generating solutions or proofs
一个更正式的版本是生成解决方案或证明
of solutions can be harder than checking them.
解决方案比检查它们更难。
Another phrasing is it's harder to generate
另一个说法是很难产生
a proof of a theorem than it is to check
一个定理的证明而不是检验
the proof of a theorem.
定理的证明。
We all know checking the proof of a theorem
我们都知道检查定理的证明
should be easy if you write it precisely.
如果您精确地写的话应该很容易。
Just make sure each step follows from the previous ones.
只要确保每个步骤都遵循先前的步骤即可。
Done.
做完了
But proving a theorem, that's hard.
但是证明一个定理很难。
You need inspiration.
您需要灵感。
You need some clever idea.
您需要一些聪明的主意。
That's guessing.
那是猜测。
Inspiration equals luck equals guessing, in this model.
在此模型中，灵感等于运气等于猜测。
And that's hard.
那很难。
The only way we know is to try all the proofs.
我们知道的唯一方法是尝试所有证明。
See which of them work.
看看其中哪个有效。
So what the heck?
那到底是什么？
What could we possibly say?
我们能说什么？
This is all kind of weird.
这真是奇怪。
This would be the end of the lecture
讲座到此结束
if you say, OK, well we don't know.
如果您说，好的，那我们不知道。
That's it.
而已。
But thankfully-- I kind of need this board.
但值得庆幸的是，我有点需要这个委员会。
I also want this one, but I guess I'll go over here.
我也想要这个，但是我想我会过去的。
Fortunately, this is not the end of the story.
幸运的是，这还不是故事的结局。
And we can say a lot about things like Tetris.
我们可以说很多有关俄罗斯方块的事情。
See I drew Tetris not just in this regime.
看到我画了俄罗斯方块，而不仅仅是在这种情况下。
We're pretty sure Tetris is between NP and P.
我们很确定俄罗斯方块在NP和P之间。
That it's in NP minus P.
它是NP减去P。
So let me write that down.
所以让我写下来。
Tetris is in NP minus P. We don't know that because we
俄罗斯方块是NP减去P。我们不知道那是因为我们
don't know-- this could be the empty set.
不知道-这可能是空集。
What we do know is that if there's
我们所知道的是，如果有
anything in NP minus P-- if they are different,
NP减去P的任何值-如果它们不同，
then-- if there's anything in NP minus P,
然后-如果NP减去P，
then Tetris is one of those things.
那么俄罗斯方块就是其中之一。
That's why I drew Tetris out there.
这就是为什么我把俄罗斯方块拉到那里。
It is, in a certain sense, the hardest problem in NP.
从某种意义上讲，这是NP中最困难的问题。
Tetris.
俄罗斯方块。
Why Tetris?
为什么选择俄罗斯方块？
Well, it's not just Tetris.
好吧，不只是俄罗斯方块。
There are a lot of problems right at that little notch.
在这个小缺口上有很多问题。
But this is pretty interesting because, while we can't figure
但这很有趣，因为尽管我们无法弄清楚
this out, most people believe this is true.
这个出来，大多数人都相信这是真的。
And so as long as you believe in that-- as long
只要您相信，
as you have faith-- then you can prove
只要有信心，就可以证明
that Tetris is in NP minus P.
俄罗斯方块是NP减去P。
And so it's hard.
所以这很难。
It's not in P, in this case.
在这种情况下，它不在P中。
In particular, not in P. That's kind of cool.
特别是P中没有。这很酷。
How in the world do we prove something like this?
我们如何证明这样的事情？
It's actually not that hard.
实际上并不难。
I mean it took us several months,
我的意思是我们花了几个月的时间
but that's just months, whereas this thing has been around
但这只是几个月，而这件事已经存在了
since, I guess, the '70s.
自70年代以来。
P versus NP.
P与NP。
Why is this true?
为什么会这样呢？
Because Tetris is NP-hard.
因为俄罗斯方块是NP硬的。
What does NP-hard mean?
NP-hard是什么意思？
This means as hard as every problem in NP.
这与NP中的每个问题一样困难。
I can't say harder than because it's non-strict.
我不能说比这更严格，因为它不是严格的。
So it's at least as hard as every problem in NP.
因此，这至少和NP中的每个问题一样困难。
And that's why I drew it at the far right.
这就是为什么我在最右边绘制它。
It's sort of the hardest extreme of NP.
这是NP最难的极端。
Among everything in NP you can possibly imagine,
在NP的所有内容中，您都可以想象到，
Tetris is as hard as all of them.
俄罗斯方块和所有人一样困难。
And therefore, if there's anything that's harder than P,
因此，如果有什么事比P难，
then Tetris is going to be harder than P because it's
那么俄罗斯方块会比P难，因为
as far to the right as possible.
尽可能地右边。
Either P equals NP, in which case the picture is like this.
P都等于NP，在这种情况下，图片就是这样。
Here's P. Here's NP.
这是P。这是NP。
Tetris is still at the right extreme, here.
在这里，俄罗斯方块仍然处于最佳状态。
But it's less interesting because it's still in P.
但这没那么有趣，因为它仍然在P中。
Or the picture looks like this, and NP is strictly
或图片看起来像这样，NP严格
bigger than P. And then, because Tetris is at the right extreme,
比P大。然后，由于俄罗斯方块处于正确的极端，
it's outside of P. So we prove this in order
它在P之外。所以我们按顺序证明这一点
to establish this claim.
确立这一主张。
Just to get some terminology, what
只是为了获得一些术语，什么
is this NP-complete business?
这是NP完整的业务吗？
Tetris is NP-complete, which means two things.
俄罗斯方块是NP完全的，这意味着两件事。
One is that it's NP-hard.
其中之一是它对NP不利。
And the other is that it's in NP.
另一个是它在NP中。
So if you think of the intersection, NP intersect
因此，如果您想到相交，NP相交
NP-hard, that's NP-complete.
NP难，那就是NP完全。
Let me draw on the picture here what this means.
让我在这里画上这是什么意思。
So I'm going to draw it on the top.
因此，我将其绘制在顶部。
This is NP-hard.
这是NP难题。
Everything from here to the right is NP-hard.
从这里到右边的所有内容都是NP-hard。
NP-hard means it's at least as hard as everything in NP.
NP困难意味着它至少与NP中的所有事物一样困难。
That means it might be at this line
这意味着可能在这一行
or it might be to the right.
或可能在右边。
But in the case of Tetris, we know that it's in NP.
但是对于俄罗斯方块，我们知道它在NP中。
We proved that a couple of times.
我们证明了几次。
And so we know that Tetris is also in this range.
因此，我们知道俄罗斯方块也在此范围内。
And so if it's in this range and in this range,
因此，如果它在此范围内，
it's got to be right here.
它必须在这里。
Completeness is nice.
完整性很好。
If you prove something is something complete--
如果您证明某件事已经完成，
prove a problem is some complexity class complete--
证明一个问题是某个复杂性课程完成了-
then you know sort of exactly where it falls on this line.
那么您就知道它在这条线上的确切位置。
NP-complete means right here.
NP-complete表示此处。
EXP-complete means right here.
EXP-complete就是这里。
Turns out Chess is EXP-complete.
事实证明，国际象棋是EXP完整的。
EXP-hard is anything from here over.
EXP-hard就是这里的一切。
EXP is anything from here, over this way.
这样就可以从这里获得EXP。
Chess is right at that borderline.
国际象棋恰好在那个边界上。
It is the hardest problem in EXP.
这是EXP中最难的问题。
And that's actually the only way we
这实际上是我们唯一的方法
know to prove that it's not NP.
知道证明它不是NP。
It's is pretty easy to show that EXP is bigger
很容易证明EXP更大
than P. And Chess is the farthest to the right in EXP--
比P. Chess在EXP中最右边-
of any problem in EXP-- and so, therefore, it's not in P.
EXP中的任何问题-因此，它不在P中。
So whereas this one-- these two, we're not sure are they equal.
因此，尽管这两个-我们不确定它们是否相等。
This line we know is different from this one.
我们知道的这一行与此不同。
We don't know about these two, though.
但是，我们不知道这两个。
Does NP equal EXP?
NP等于EXP吗？
Not as famous.
没有那么出名。
You won't get a million dollars, but still a very big,
你不会得到一百万美元，但仍然是非常大的，
open question.
悬而未决的问题。
What else do I wanna say?
我还要说什么？
Tetris, Chess, EXP-hard.
俄罗斯方块，国际象棋，EXP难度。
So these lines, here-- this is NP-complete
这些行，这是NP完整的
And this is EXP-complete.
这是EXP完整的。
So the last thing I want to talk about is reductions.
因此，我要谈的最后一件事是减少费用。
Reductions-- so how do you prove something like this?
减少-那么您如何证明这样的事情？
What is as hard as even mean?
到底有什么困难？
I haven't defined that.
我还没有定义。
But it's not hard to define.
但这并不难定义。
In fact, it's a concept we've seen already.
实际上，这是我们已经看到的概念。
Reductions are actually a way to design algorithms
归约实际上是设计算法的一种方式
that we've been using implicitly a lot.
我们已经隐式地使用了很多。
You may have even heard this term.
您甚至可能听说过这个学期。
A bunch of recitations have used the word reduction
一堆背诵都使用了减少词
for graph reduction.
用于图形还原。
You have some problem, you convert it
您遇到问题，将其转换
into a graph problem, then you just call the graph algorithm.
陷入图问题，那么您只需调用图算法即可。
You're done.
你完成了。
That's reduction.
那是减少。
In general, you have some problem, A,
一般来说，您有一些问题，A，
that you want to solve.
您要解决的问题。
And you convert it into some other problem, B,
然后将其转换为其他问题B
that you already know how to solve.
您已经知道如何解决。
It's a great tool because, in this class,
这是一个很棒的工具，因为在本课程中，
you learn tons of algorithms for solving tons of problems.
您将学习大量的算法来解决大量的问题。
Now, someone gives you, in your job or whatever,
现在，有人给您，无论您的工作是什么，
or you think about some problem that you
或您想到一些您遇到的问题
don't know how to solve, the first thing you should
不知道该怎么解决，你应该做的第一件事
do is-- can I convert it into something
我要做的是-我可以将其转换为某种东西吗
I know how to solve because then you're done.
我知道如何解决，因为到此为止。
Now it may not be the best way to solve it,
现在，它可能不是解决问题的最佳方法，
but at least it's a way to solve it.
但这至少是解决问题的一种方法。
Probably in polynomial time because we think of B as things
可能在多项式时间内，因为我们将B视为事物
you can solve in polynomial time.
您可以在多项式时间内求解。
Great.
大。
So just convert problem A, which you
所以只要转换问题A
want to solve, into some problem B that you know how to solve.
想解决，解决一些您知道如何解决的问题B。
That's reduction.
那是减少。
Let me give you some examples that we've already seen,
让我给你一些我们已经看到的例子，
just to fit this into your mental map of the class.
只是为了使其适合您的班级心理图。
It's kind of a funny one but it's a very simple one.
这很有趣，但是却很简单。
So how do you solve unweighted shortest paths?
那么如何解决未加权的最短路径呢？
In general?
一般来说？
Easy one.
简单的。
Give you a graph with no weights on the edges and I
给你一个没有权重的图，我
want to the shortest path from s to t.
想要从s到t的最短路径。
AUDIENCE: BFS
观众：BFS
PROFESSOR: BFS.
教授：BFS。
Linear time, right?
线性时间，对吗？
Well, that's if you're smart or if you
好吧，那是如果你很聪明或者
feel like implementing BFS.
感觉像实施BFS。
Suppose someone gave you Djikstra.
假设有人给了你Djikstra。
Said, here, look, I've got Djikstra code.
说，这里，看，我有Djikstra代码。
You don't have to do anything.
您不必做任何事情。
There's Djisktra code right there.
那里有Djisktra代码。
But Djikstra solves weighted shortest path.
但是Djikstra解决了加权最短路径。
I don't have any weights.
我没有体重。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
Set the weights to 1.
将权重设置为1。
It's very easy, but this is a reduction--
这很简单，但这是一种减少-
a simple example of reduction.
减少的一个简单例子。
Not the smartest of reductions, but it's a reduction.
不是最明智的削减方法，而是削减方法。
So I can convert unweighted shortest paths
这样我就可以转换未加权的最短路径
into weighted shortest paths by adding weights of 1.
通过增加权重1进入加权最短路径。
Done.
做完了
Adding weights of 0 would not work.
将权重加0将不起作用。
But weights of 1.
但是权重为1。
OK.
好。
Weights of 2 also works.
权重2也可以。
Pick your favorite number, but as long as you're consistent
选择您喜欢的号码，但只要您保持一致
about it.
关于它。
That's a reduction.
减少了。
Here's some more interesting ones.
这是一些更有趣的。
On the problems set-- problem set six--
关于问题集-问题集6-
there was this RenBook problem, "I Can Haz Moar Frendz?"
有一个RenBook问题，“我能阻止Moar Frendz吗？”
That was the name of the problem.
那就是问题的名字。
And the goal was to solve-- to find
目标是解决-找到
paths that minimize the product of weights.
使重量乘积最小的路径。
But what we've covered in class is
但是我们在课堂上讲的是
how to solve a problem when it's the sum of weights.
权重之和时如何解决问题。
How do you do it?
你怎么做呢？
In one word, or less?
一句话，还是更少？
Logs.
日志。
Just take logs.
只是拿日志。
That converts products into sums.
这将乘积转换为总和。
Now you start to get the flavor.
现在您开始得到味道。
This is a problem that you could take Djikstra or Bellman-Ford,
这是您可能需要Djikstra或Bellman-Ford的问题，
and change all the relaxation steps
并更改所有放松步骤
and change it to work directly with products.
并将其更改为直接用于产品。
That would work, but it's more work.
可以，但是还需要更多工作。
You have to prove that that's still correct.
您必须证明那是正确的。
It's annoying to think about.
考虑到这很烦人。
And it's annoying to program.
而且编程很烦人。
It's not modular, blah, blah, blah.
它不是模块化的，等等，等等。
Whereas if you just do this reduction,
而如果您只是这样做，
you can use exactly the code that you had before,
您可以完全使用以前的代码，
at the end.
在末尾。
So that's nice.
很好。
This is why reductions are really
这就是为什么减少是真正的
the most common algorithm design technique because you don't
最常见的算法设计技术，因为您没有
want to implement an algorithm for every single problem you
想要为您的每个问题实施一种算法
have.
有。
It would be nice if you could reuse some of those algorithms
如果您可以重用其中一些算法，那就太好了
that you had before.
你以前有过
Reductions let you do that.
减少可让您做到这一点。
Another one, which was on the quiz in the true-false-- quiz
另一个是对-假-测验中的测验
two-- was converting longest path into shortest path.
二-将最长的路径转换为最短的路径。
We didn't phrase it as a reduction.
我们没有把它说成是减少。
It was just can you solve longest path using
只是您能解决使用
Bellman-Ford.
贝尔曼福特。
And the answer is yes.
答案是肯定的。
You just negate all the weights.
您只需取消所有权重。
And that converts a longest path problem
这会转换最长路径问题
into a shortest path problem.
进入最短路径问题。
Easy.
简单。
Also on the quiz-- maybe I don't need to write all of these down
同样在测验中-也许我不需要将所有这些写下来
because they're a little bit weird problems.
因为它们有一些奇怪的问题。
We made them up.
我们弥补了。
There was the-- what was the duck tour called?
鸭子之旅叫什么？
Bird tours?
鸟之旅？
Aviation tours?
航空旅行？
Whatever.
随你。
You want to visit a bunch of sites in some specified order.
您想按指定的顺序访问许多站点。
The point in that problem is you could reduce it
该问题的关键是您可以减少它
to a single shortest paths query.
到最短路径查询。
And so if you already have shortest path code,
因此，如果您已经拥有最短的路径代码，
you don't have to think much.
您不必考虑太多。
You just do the graph application.
您只需执行图形应用程序即可。
Done.
做完了
Then there's the leaky tank problem,
然后是水箱漏水的问题，
which is also a graph reduction problem.
这也是图形还原的问题。
You could represent all these extra weird things
您可以代表所有这些额外的怪异事物
that were happening in your car by just
只是在你的车里发生的
changing the graph a little bit.
稍微改变一下图。
And it's a very powerful technique.
这是一项非常强大的技术。
In this class, we see it mostly in graph reductions.
在此类中，我们主要在图形约简中看到它。
But it could apply all over the place.
但这可能适用于整个地方。
And while this is a powerful technique for coming up
虽然这是一种强大的技巧
with new algorithms, it's also a powerful technique
有了新算法，这也是一项强大的技术
for proving things like Tetris is NP-hard.
证明俄罗斯方块之类的东西很难。
So what we proved is that a problem
所以我们证明这是一个问题
called 3-Partition can be reduced to Tetris.
所谓的三分区可以简化为俄罗斯方块。
What's 3-Partition?
什么是3分区？
3-Partition is I give you n numbers.
三分区是我给你n个数字。
I want to know can I divide them into triples,
我想知道是否可以将它们分为三部分，
each of the same sum.
每个都相同。
So I have n numbers.
所以我有n个数字。
Divide them into n over 3 groups of 3,
将它们分成3组，每组3个，n个，
such that the sum of each of the 3s is equal.
使得3s的总和相等。
Sounds like an easy enough problem.
听起来很简单。
But it's an NP-complete problem.
但这是一个NP完全问题。
And people knew that since one of the first papers.
自从第一批论文以来，人们就知道这一点。
I guess that was late '70s, early '80s, by Karp.
我猜那是Karp在70年代末80年代初。
So Karp already proved this is standing
所以卡普已经证明了这一点
on the shoulders of giants.
在巨人的肩膀上。
Karp proved 3-Partition is NP-complete,
卡普证明3分区是NP完全的，
so I don't need to think about that.
所以我不需要考虑这一点。
All I need to focus on is showing
我需要专注的是展示
that Tetris is harder than 3-Partition.
俄罗斯方块比三分区更难。
This is what I mean by harder.
这就是我的意思。
Harder means-- so when I can reduce A to B,
比较难的意思-所以当我可以将A减为B时，
we say the A-- B is at least as hard as A. Why's that?
我们说A– B至少和A一样难。为什么呢？
Because I can solve A by solving B. I just apply this reduction
因为我可以通过解决B来解决A。
and then solve B. So if I had some good way to solve B,
然后解决B。所以如果我有解决B的好方法，
it would turn into a good way to solve A.
这将成为解决A的好方法。
Now 3-Partition-- which is A, here-- we're
现在3分区-在这里是A-我们是
pretty sure there's no good algorithm for solving this.
很确定没有解决这个问题的好算法。
Pretty sure it's not in P. And so Tetris better not be P
可以肯定它不在P中。所以俄罗斯方块最好不要成为P
either because if Tetris were in P, then
要么因为如果俄罗斯方块在P中，
we could just take our 3-Partition,
我们可以采用3分区，
reduce it to Tetris, and then 3-Partition would be in P.
将其还原为Tetris，然后将3分区放在P中。
In fact, all of the NP-complete problems,
实际上，所有NP完全问题，
you can reduce to each other.
您可以互相减少。
And so to show that something is at that little position,
因此，为了表明某物处于那个小位置，
NP-complete, all you need to do is
NP完成，您需要做的就是
find some known NP-complete problem
找到一些已知的NP完全问题
and reduce it to your problem.
并减少到您的问题。
So reductions are super useful for getting positive results
因此，减少对于获得积极结果非常有用
for making new algorithms, but also
制作新算法，而且
for proving negative results-- showing that one problem is
用于证明负面结果-表明一个问题是
harder than another.
比另一个更难。
And if you already believe this is hard,
如果您已经相信这很困难，
then you should believe this is hard.
那么您应该相信这很难。
I think that's all I really have time for.
我想这就是我真正有时间的。
I'll give you a couple more NP-complete problems.
我再给您几个NP完全问题。
Kind of fun.
有点乐趣。
Traveling salesman problem, you may have heard of.
您可能听说过旅行商的问题。
Let's say you have a graph.
假设您有一张图表。
And you want to find out the shortest path that
您想找出最短的路径
visits all the vertices, not just one vertex.
访问所有顶点，而不仅仅是一个顶点。
That's NP-complete.
那是NP完成的。
We solved longest common subsequence for two strings,
我们解决了两个字符串的最长公共子序列，
but if I give you n strings that you
但是如果我给你n个弦，你
need to find the longest common subsequence of,
需要找到最长的公共子序列
that's NP-complete.
那是NP完成的。
Minesweeper, Sudoku, most puzzles that are interesting
扫雷，数独，大多数有趣的难题
are NP-complete.
是NP完全的。
SAT.
SAT。
SAT is a-- I give you a Boolean formula like x or y AND NOT
SAT是-我给你一个布尔公式，例如x或y
x-- something like that.
x-像这样。
I want to know is there some setting of the variables that
我想知道是否有一些变量设置
makes this thing come out true?
使这件事成真？
Is it possible to make this true?
是否有可能做到这一点？
That's NP-complete complete.
那是NP完全完成。
This was actually the first problem
这实际上是第一个问题
that was shown NP-complete.
显示为NP完整。
There's this issue, right?
有这个问题吧？
If I'm going to show everything's NP-complete
如果我要显示所有的NP完成
by reduction, how the heck do I get started?
通过减少，我该如何开始？
What's the first problem?
第一个问题是什么？
And this is the first problem.
这是第一个问题。
You could sort of prove it by definition, almost, of NP,
您几乎可以通过NP的定义来证明这一点，
here.
这里。
But I won't do that.
但是我不会那样做。
Three coloring a graph.
三着色图形。
Shortest paths.
最短路径。
This is fun.
这好有趣。
Shortest paths in a graph is hard.
图中的最短路径很难。
But in the real world, we live in a three dimensional,
但是在现实世界中，我们生活在一个三维空间中
geometric environment.
几何环境。
What if I want to find the shortest
如果我想找到最短的怎么办
path from this point, where I am, to that point,
从这一点到我现在的路径，
over on the ceiling or something.
在天花板上或其他东西上。
And I can fly.
我会飞。
That's NP-complete.
那是NP完成的。
It's kind of weird.
有点奇怪
Shortest paths in a two dimensional environment
二维环境中的最短路径
is polynomial.
是多项式。
It's a good thing that we are on ground because, then, we
我们站在地面上是一件好事，因为我们
can model things by two dimensions.
可以按二维模型化事物。
We can model things by graphs.
我们可以通过图来建模。
But in 3D, shortest paths is NP-complete.
但是在3D中，最短路径是NP完整的。
So all these things where a problem-- knapsack,
所以所有这些都有问题的地方-背包，
that's another one.
那是另一种。
We've already covered knapsack.
我们已经介绍了背包。
We saw a pseudo-polynomial algorithm.
我们看到了伪多项式算法。
Turns out, you can't do better than pseudo-polynomial
事实证明，没有比伪多项式更好的了
unless P equals NP because knapsack is NP-complete.
除非P等于NP，因为背包是NP完全的。
So there you go.
所以你去了。
Computational complexity in 50 minutes.
50分钟即可实现计算复杂性。